[Music]
Welcome to Business Central launch event
2025 release wave 1. In this session, we
will show you some new enhancements
related to e document matching copilot.
So let's first see what is new in e
document matching copilot.
uh one of the first thing what is really
new and this is based on your feedback.
Now we support all different types of uh
entries. So earlier we supported only
general ledger accounts and items but
now you can handle with resources with
uh item charge with everything. Second
is that we now we can include extra
lines into a purchase order
automatically from inbound invoice. Just
imagine we had uh some lines in our
purchase order but then we got
electronic invoice with one additional
line for example transport cost and we
couldn't resolve this earlier. Now you
can automatically add this line to
purchase order from uh matching page and
third one is and has auto matching
capabilities into copilot prompts adding
uh not only 80% of similarity but adding
item references as well. So let's see
first process flow how it work earlier.
We had some purchase order as I
mentioned with for example two items and
then we got incoming document with two
items for now just look these two items
and we had maybe different uh expression
different descriptions but when we run a
matching page and copilot everything was
matched perfect case and we could post
our electronic invoice in purchase order
without any problem. But what if we have
this one additional line? So we have
additional expense on this electronic
voice and we didn't plan for that. We
cannot complain to our vendor because
this is obviously why we got this
additional line. And now what we could
earlier we could go earlier back to
purchase order to create manually but it
was a problem automatically from
matching page it was not possible. So
when you wanted to uh confirm to post it
was not possible because you had this
one additional expense and you couldn't
proceed because you had to post
completely invoice not partially
invoice. So it was a problem and what we
did now now we added additional option
adding um line automatically from
incoming document from electronic
incoming document. So now you can mark
and you can choose what type of line you
want to get because maybe this line can
be GL account, maybe it can be item
charge, resource, whatever you want.
This is just unplanned line and you can
decide what you want to create in a in a
uh purchase order and after that you can
continue with matching and uh uh
proceeding for posting document. You can
also decide to save this for the future
uh usage. if we talk about items and GL
accounts because we do not have item
references or GL mapping for other
options. So this is what we did in this
process flow. So now we enabled adding
new lines and plus adding different
types not only items and GL account. And
as I mentioned third one is that
previously we work for auto matching not
running LLM matching. We previously work
only if we had 80% of string similarity
but now we added item references. So if
we already have item reference existing
it reference system will treat this as
an auto matching and will not run LLM
for uh dispatching and plus now you have
on your prompt you have an option to
mark every every time when LLM finds
some similarity some match you can mark
the system will automatically create
item reference for future usage. So this
is in general what we improved in uh
matching copilot for purchase order. Now
I will give a word and my colleague
Andre so he can show you in a demo how
it
works. Yeah, thank you. So let's see
this in action. Now um here I have a new
business central tenant that I have set
up and uh in here I can go to my e
documents. I already have an e document
imported e document number one that we
can take a look at. So let me try and
open the matching page for this e
document. And on the left hand side you
can here see the invoice that we have
received. And on the right hand side we
see the purchase
order. Now if I just try and do an
automatic matching here. So if I click
here you see nothing actually happens.
The reason is that we haven't set up any
item references for any of these items
and the strings doesn't match with an
80% accuracy. So we can't be certain
that these will should actually be
matched. Instead what we can do is use
copilot. This is existing functionality
where we can click uh this match with
copilot. copilot is called and very
quickly responds back with uh which
lines it uh thinks should be matched.
now existing functionality and as you
can see here it was able to match
everything except uh one line uh and
that's because and I'll get back to that
in a moment but we have a uh transfer
cost as well which we haven't put into
our purchase order which is going to be
uh where we look at how can we actually
create this quickly um as well but
before we get to that we see copile has
matched our five lines with the three
lines we had in our purchase order. And
we can simply now click uh keep this.
But we have a new field called learn
matching rule. This uh field allows you
to actually have Business Central learn
this matching rule such that it knows
for instance if I click uh learn
matching rule for the espresso roast
beans and Mexican mocka beans it will
learn to match that with the item on
this line. uh that means we are making
an item reference in the background and
in the future we can automatically match
this and we don't need to call copilot
every single time for this one. So now
let me click keep this and you can see
first of all copilot has matched all the
lines which is great uh except for this
transport uh service which we'll get
back to but also just to show you what
we was actually created behind the
scenes because we now selected to create
uh to learn this matching rule. If we go
to the item and go to item
references, you'll see there are now two
item references for our vendor when two
20,000 and it's uh yeah these two item
references the unit of measures and we
can even see that this was
autogenerated from um the E document
number one. So we can backtrack. Why was
this actually
created? Now let's get back into the
matching page. So now that we have this
item reference, it actually means that
we can now automatically match this. So
if I click auto match, it means we're
going to remove all the matching copile
did and only use automatic matching. And
in this case, we can now see we actually
able to match these two lines up because
I create this rule. And from now on,
these will automatically be matched up
against these lines in the future. So
you no longer need to call copilot for
that. So that's um this will greatly
speed up uh the matching that you're
doing and make it more reliable.
Now furthermore, uh we also have this um
new line that I talked about this
transport
service. Well, as you can see, we don't
have this in the purchase order. There
could be multiple reasons for this.
Maybe we forgot about it. Maybe um it's
on purpose or some other reason. But
either way, we now need to actually
create this in our purchase order. And
to do that originally, you would have to
go to document purchase order, then go
to lines, create a new line. Uh then you
would create a a charge item or whatever
it is and fill in. You have to remember
what are the amounts and all of that.
Fill that in here. Then you go back and
realize, hey, actually charge items
doesn't show up and you need to figure
out how to work around that. Now we
actually support uh all these other
types and furthermore so all of these
types will show up not just items and GL
accounts. So you can do that but I want
to show an even easier way we have now
to do that. Basically on the imported
lines you can now click the three dots
and we have this create purchase order
line. This is a simple simplified way to
quickly create a purchase order line
from this invoice line. When you click
that, you'll see this new page which uh
automatically populates the units of
unit of measures and the cost for this
such that you don't get those incorrect
and make sure that this matches up. If
you want something more uh complex, you
can always go back to the invoice itself
and uh create it however you like. Now
let's create this charge item. And this
might be a freight item. And we can
actually change even the quantity. You
can see right now it's 500. If I change
this to two, we'll change the unit of
measure such that we can match this
after uh afterwards.
Finally, we also have this learn
matching rule. Now, this only works for
GL accounts and items. So, GL accounts,
we use the text to account mapping if
you're familiar with that. And item
references we use the for items we use
item references. So, for other the other
types, this not going to do anything.
It's also explained in there and we'll
uh let you know if you try and we can't
do
it. Then let's click okay. And
automatically you can see a new charge
item has been created in the purchase
order. I can even open up the purchase
order. And you can see in here in the
purchase order that we now have the new
charge item.
Now let's go back to the matching page.
And now we can actually go ahead and
match these up. So I can say for
instance match all manually. Now these
two lines are matched. And you can go
ahead proceed and actually uh post your
invoice. So that's it for me and back to
you Alexander. Thank you. So now you can
see that we have some new things here
improvements. It doesn't mean that this
is everything. Uh this is what we try to
to improve based on your feedback on
your usage of this copilot. Idea is to
continue improvements in next waves
before we finally enable this as a
general aability. So currently this is
still a public preview because we want
to improve in a few more places and
please if you know any idea what should
be done here let us know. So thank you
for watching this video.